[tense music playing]
[exhales sharply]
[siren blaring]
[siren stops]
[man on radio] Units maintain position.
No activity reported.
[Mélanie] Okay. Yeah.
[man] Move over there.
[indistinct radio chatter]
[rifle safety clicks]
- Establish a perimeter around the vehicle.
- Copy.
[man on radio] Maintain position.
No activity reported.
[officers chattering indistinctly]
[Mélanie sighs]
Commander Berger. you know the procedure.
I'm placing you under arrest.
Yeah.
ELITE FORCE
Sorry to have kept you waiting. Commander.
I'm sure this won't take long.
[door slams]
[power-on beep]
I just have a… a few questions for you.
Clarifications.
Now. you said your phone…
that you left it in your locker?
Yeah. that's right.
I forgot it in my locker.
- Hm. It's not like you to be unreachable.
- My mind was elsewhere.
I don't make a habit
of revisiting painful memories.
I was pretty distraught. so… yeah.
You went to visit the place
where your former partner was killed.
On the anniversary of his death. right?
Have you ever gone to visit the place
in the 15 years since you… lost him?
Since he died?
No.
Why this year?
Maybe because of Christophe.
I just felt like I had to.
To pay your respects.
Yeah.
Armed with an AK-47
and a pump-action shotgun.
I'm a cautious kind of person.
You can understand that given my history.
I'm also quite a cautious person.
But it wouldn't cross my mind
to bring an arsenal with me
to visit my father's grave.
I think. possibly.
the difference between you and me
is how dangerous
our respective professions are.
Have you ever been targeted by a car bomb
in the course of your work?
You or your father?
Have you ever been. let's say.
maybe anxious. or terrified.
that because of what you do every day.
you might not make it home alive?
That you might not be able
to see your family?
And maybe if your job was.
I don't know. a bit more dangerous
than simply handing out fines
to people doing their jobs.
you might see things
a bit different. perhaps.
My father was a general
in the armed forces.
Great point. though.
I'm still struggling to understand
something about the weapons.
- [David sighs]
- None of them were registered anywhere.
There are no permits for them.
They're not authorized for the field.
The weapons were seized
during a recent mission.
I followed all the necessary steps
to have them regulated and made official.
I imagine the papers
just got lost in the shuffle.
So much bureaucratic red tape. you know.
Mea culpa.
I accept the fine.
[scoffs]
Would you?
SEALED - DO NOT OPEN
90 rounds of ammo for the AK-47.
and 30 Brenneke shells for the shotgun.
I'm confused. Commander.
I believe these aren't standard issue?
We choose our ammunition
to suit the mission.
which you would know if you took
the slightest interest in our work.
So? What kind of mission
would require this type of gear?
One that demands overwhelming force.
[scoffs]
Just so I make sure
I understand correctly.
you commandeered
an unregistered shotgun and rifle.
with ammunition specially chosen
because of its firepower.
You drove yourself to the site
of your former partner's death.
illegally breaking
into a military site in the process.
something you've never done before.
not once in 15 years.
and there.
perhaps coincidentally. or by fate.
you come across Mr. Mayard.
The sole suspect in the killing
of your commanding officer.
You go to bring him in.
and despite your. um… expertise
and your many years' experience at GIGN.
he grabs a weapon.
so you have to kill him. Is that right?
Minus that hint of sarcasm. correct.
I promised that if you
stepped out of line ever again.
it would be the last time.
I'm a woman of my word.
You're not coming back from this.
[dramatic music playing]
[indistinct chatter]
[dramatic music continues]
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org
[door opens]
[woman] Now we both know. All right?
[woman speaking indistinctly]
[knocking]
[Mélanie] Yes?
[door opens]
Mrs. Berger. come on in.
[door closes]
That's a police report.
It was filed
by one of your daughter's friends.
relating to events that took place
at his home. at a party.
The young man describes
an altercation between David Berger
and several of his guests.
If this were serious.
the prosecutor on this case
would be laying charges on my husband.
But this is just a police report.
You're absolutely right.
The young man in question
claimed he had too much to drink.
and withdrew his statement.
The prosecutor was therefore
unable to pursue the case.
So. what? Why are you telling me this?
Your husband
is formally trained in combat.
He's more than capable in a fight.
In short. he's a weapon.
So when it's one o'clock in the morning.
his daughter's not answering her phone.
maybe he panics.
And when he finds this guy…
he tases him.
The question I'm asking myself.
Mrs. Berger.
is how far your husband's willing to go
when his family's on the line?
[tense music playing]
[Jess exhales]
David's calling is to protect.
You. me. his daughter. everyone.
The mission above all else. Always.
He's just doing his job.
And the premeditated murder of a suspect?
That's just him doing his job as well?
How long have you been working
with Commander Berger?
Five years.
A bit longer.
[tense music continues]
[Mélanie] How would you
describe his leadership?
Exemplary.
Would you describe yourselves as close?
You and Berger?
We're all brothers-in-arms.
The GIGN is one big family.
Hm.
There's no sound in this video.
but do you happen to recall
what you were saying to him here?
Not really. no. probably nothing special.
Something about our kids.
training. recruits.
And this bag. it seems quite heavy.
Any idea what might be in it?
[chuckles softly]
It's from the armory. it's a tactical bag.
You know exactly what's in there.
Why bother asking?
[Mélanie] You didn't have
any shooting drills
planned for that day. though. did you?
Why take out weapons?
Each one of us is an elite marksman.
We spend plenty of time training.
That's not surprising.
You seem a bit surprised in the video.
If that's your interpretation.
[sighs]
I think you knew
the commander wasn't using
that bag for training purposes.
I think you tried to warn him.
because you're a good person.
Loyal too.
An admirable quality.
But loyal to whom?
That's what you should be asking.
Loyal to your men?
Or to your friend?
Do you think that driving out
to a decommissioned military base
in the middle of the night.
stumbling upon a heavily armed suspect.
and shooting him to death
is responsible behavior?
Is that the behavior of a GIGN leader?
The commander made a call.
Which was revenge. At the cost
of the entire institution's reputation.
I won't even mention
the CL-20 that's disappeared
that we have no hope of ever seeing again
now that our primary suspect is dead.
What about you. Major?
Who are you loyal to?
[exhales]
Tsk.
[sighs]
During the encounter with Kröller.
when we were hit
by the sniper in the forest. uh…
I can't be sure. but…
I think he walked off with something.
[Mélanie] Where were you last night?
[tense music continues]
I was at home. Alone in my apartment.
[Mélanie] You weren't.
You were there when he killed Mayard.
You deliberately
concealed your presence there.
Do you know what happens next?
Your career is over.
[door opens]
[footsteps approach]
[door closes]
[ominous music playing]
[Mélanie] You know what this is?
Looks like a cartridge used by the sniper
who ambushed us in the forest
and killed the arms dealer. Kröller.
We found it in your home.
Any idea why this might have been
in your apartment?
As you know. long-range shooting
is one of my specialties. so…
I've accumulated
a few cartridges over the years.
Why do you think we went out of our way
to search your house?
You're stubborn?
Major Bonenfant. your “brother-in-arms.”
your friend. your colleague. Cédric.
He's the one who told me to look.
You're aware that removing evidence
from a crime scene
is in itself a crime
and would be grounds for a court martial?
- But maybe it's a coincidence.
- [exhales]
Like the weapons you took from the armory.
like the fact that you were
in the right place. at the right time.
to take down the terrorist
everyone was looking for.
But I have another explanation.
Take a guess.
Tsk. [sighs]
Flashback to the night of the graduation.
Your superior. your mentor.
the man who taught you
everything you know.
Christophe. is attacked.
Your world falls apart.
So you start your own investigation.
You illegally interrogate a suspect
you just had arrested.
You take away evidence from a crime scene.
You track down Mayard.
but he slips through your fingers
at the hospital.
You keep searching.
You use your colleague's computer.
And then you find the guy.
You go after him.
And your investigation results
in personal. punitive justice.
[door opens]
Commander. a word. please?
[slams door]
Whenever a shot is fired. my men
are questioned. That's the procedure.
I don't get involved
because it falls to the local police.
Now I learn it's Internal Investigations
that's been questioning my men
without telling me!
Explain that.
I heard you brought in
David's wife for questioning.
I just need to know
if this is you being overzealous.
or if we've got a problem.
Come in.
[door opens]
The SD card from your vehicle's dash cam
has mysteriously disappeared.
Another coincidence.
Fortunately. the dash cam's software
was updated.
The footage gets uploaded to a server
and I was able
to access the recording remotely.
[general] Villiers?
[tense music playing]
- [general] David?
- [Mélanie] We all know you're guilty.
The question now
is whether you'll get jail time.
When did you make the decision
to kill Mayard?
And what role did your godson
play in your plan?
Can you stop recording for a minute?
And can he leave the room?
[exhales]
[footsteps receding]
[door opens]
[door closes]
I'll confess to everything. The murder.
the weapons. the premeditation too.
But on two conditions.
The first is that Max
isn't dragged into this.
He didn't know my plan
before following me.
and I forced him
to keep quiet after the fact.
The second…
is that you let me
go home tonight. alright?
See my family.
I'll provide a full confession tomorrow.
You're still trying
to bend the rules to your advantage.
even after getting caught.
Why would I accept?
Why wouldn't you accept
is a better question.
For the moment. all you have
is a lie about Max's involvement
in the whole situation.
And a small series of minor infractions.
Not much to go on.
We've got more than enough here
to discharge you and Max.
- Yeah.
- Mm.
But what would bring you
more satisfaction?
Getting me kicked off the force?
Or the chance to see me behind bars?
- [dramatic music playing]
- [indistinct chatter]
- Hey. you guys still awake?
- Hey. good. thanks.
- Hey.
- All good?
- All good.
- Hey.
[instructor] Come on let's keep it up!
[Cédric] Alright. move it!
[man] Right. a little lower.
just a bit lower! And in on three!
One. two. three! Let's go.
- [instructor] Inside!
- [Cédric] Advance!
[instructor] Good. breach the window!
Let's keep it moving. boys!
[Cédric] You're taking too long.
Ten seconds and you're dead. got it?
[instructor] Move up.
take a right. Right. now!
[dramatic poignant music playing]
[instructor] Go right!
Advance!
Hold here!
[Cédric] Good work. debrief in ten.
Get changed and regroup at HQ.
[dramatic poignant music continues]
We're with you. okay?
You alright?
Hey. asshole.
[dramatic poignant music continues]
If you wanna talk. I'm around.
It wouldn't change a thing.
[dramatic poignant music continues]
[exhales]
[sighs]
[motorcycle passes]
[music fades]
- [indistinct chatter]
- [sighs]
Where were you?
[door closes]
I'm not here to talk.
["My Chemical Soul"
by Laura Crow & Him playing]
♪ You should not believe
All that you see ♪
♪ When they take control over me ♪
♪ Forgive me if I'm cynical ♪
♪ I'm driven by chemicals ♪
[playing "Impromptu No. 2"
by Franz Schubert]
[footsteps approaching]
[sighs]
Since when does Internal
interrogate wives?
She's overzealous. that's all.
She thinks you executed
Christophe's killer.
Why'd she let you go early?
They normally keep you for 24 hours.
Because I confessed.
You what?
I made a deal with her.
I'm signing anything she wants tomorrow.
In exchange. she's letting me
spend the night with you.
The night?
What are you talking about?
Did you kill him or didn't you?
I would've.
[scoffs]
What've you done? I can't believe this.
You'll go to prison!
[piano playing continues]
It's because Max is involved. isn't it?
You don't owe him anything!
[exhales. inhales sharply]
What about Manon. David?
You think I want to do this?
You think this is easy for me?
I don't have a choice.
It's Max.
I have to help.
It means nothing if you're here tonight
but can't be tomorrow.
Nothing.
[music ends]
[Max sighs]
Where are you going?
It was fun. I gotta go.
Hang on.
You can't just go dark.
then show up at my door and say nothing.
I told you. I wasn't here to talk.
This is about David. right?
Because he killed the terrorist?
He cleaned out his locker.
Apparently they fired him.
[Max sighs]
David didn't pull the trigger.
I did.
Wait. what?
[dramatic music playing]
Uh. what are you saying?
I followed David. I was there.
We stopped the guy together.
but it all went to shit.
I fucked up.
So. why is David the one being fired
if you shot the guy?
He told Internal Investigations
it was him.
Left me out.
He's doing it for me.
And you're gonna let him?
He's been lying from the start.
Before he died. Mayard said that it's
David's fault that my dad was killed.
How does that justify
what they're doing to him now?
He needs to pay for what he's done.
I agree. he does. of course.
But not like this.
[music fades]
[motor revving]
[motor shuts off]
- I'm gonna tell them the truth.
- Don't do that.
Look at me.
Max. if you do this. you're done.
My career's already over.
- But that's…
- [door opens]
[poignant music playing]
My dad. Mayard said
it was your fault what happened to him.
David. you're about
to destroy your life for me
when a month ago.
you barely knew I existed.
- Max…
- All I can think of is. you feel guilty.
So unless you're ready to explain why
you're willing to sacrifice everything.
I'm telling them the truth.
[Christophe] The lone terrorist
used to work at the lab. He's an idealist.
Angry about weapons they develop here.
he wants all of France to know.
All they told me is that it's explosives.
Work in teams of two. usual partners.
Standard rules of engagement.
reasonable self-defense.
Imminent threat to a hostage's life.
or a direct order.
Okay. everyone? Let's move!
- [tense music playing]
- [man] Guys. let's move out.
[indistinct chatter]
Christophe. I wanna change partners.
Change partners? Why?
It's better this way.
Right. listen up. you two.
I don't care what your problem is.
just handle it.
There's a terrorist.
and 21 hostages that need us.
You either make me regret
putting you in the field.
or you figure your shit out.
Okay.
[suspenseful music playing]
[door unlocks]
- My daughter.
- [operator] Go! Go! Let's move it!
Doc! Let's go!
Listen. I'm a father too. okay?
- I'm a father. I'll get your daughter.
- [fading] The lab…
- We're getting out of here. now!
- [David] No. wait!
This way. come on! Here!
We gotta be out in 50 seconds.
- Lina!
- [David] Lina?
[Christophe on comm]
Everyone. to the exits!
- [David] Lina. we're with your parents!
- Turn around. Get your asses outta there!
- You copy?
- [David] Lina!
- [Christophe] Emergency procedure.
- [Christophe] Get out. right now!
- Lina!
Lina. if you're hiding in here.
you have to come out!
David.
- I can't wait any longer. I'm doing it.
- [Laurent] Lina!
- [David] Lina!
- [sighs]
- [alarm blaring]
- Laurent. we gotta move. Ah. fuck.
- [Laurent] Lina!
- Laurent. let's go! Shit!
- [Christophe] David. that's an order! Out!
- We have to go!
Not until we've found her. Lina!
- We have to fucking go. now!
- Lina!
- Come on. move it!
- Let go!
Let go of me!
- [grunts]
- Get your hands off me! Don't touch me.
Wait. Laurent.
You know she's not here.
It's gonna blow. we've gotta leave.
- So. then leave! You can fucking go!
- [gasps]
[alarm blaring]
[door whirring]
[door locks]
[dramatic music playing]
[David grunting]
[Laurent] David.
Look at me!
[pants] Just go. David.
- There's gotta be another way outta here.
- There isn't.
We both know it. Just go. please.
Please.
I'm sorry. Laurent.
I'm so sorry.
[David sobbing]
[breathes shakily]
Take care of Max.
Okay.
Get outta here.
I said run!
[dramatic music continues]
[tools crashing]
[exhales]
[Laurent] I knew you were here.
I'm Laurent.
Come with me?
[alarm blaring]
It'll be okay.
Is Mommy going to come and get me?
[Laurent] Yeah. she's almost here.
[muffled explosion]
[music fades]
There's something I don't understand.
If none of this was your fault.
then why do this for me?
Because it's still partially my fault.
I mean that. uh… if Laurent's emotions
got the better of him.
I played a part in that.
[poignant music playing]
He'd just received some results.
He found out he couldn't have children.
That he'd never been able to.
I'd held on to the secret for years.
at your mother's request but…
I couldn't do it anymore.
Max. I'm your dad.
I know that… I know that I haven't really
been there for you since Laurent died.
Your mother wanted me to keep my distance.
so I listened to her.
Maybe I was an idiot for staying away.
I don't know.
[poignant music continues]
I-I-I just know I can't go back.
I can't change what happened.
But I can make a difference now.
For you.
I can protect you.
[Mélanie] We weren't expecting you
this morning. Major Villiers.
[footsteps approach]
Can we talk?
Of course.
[door opens]
[poignant music continues]
[exhales]
I'll tell you what really happened.
[music fades]
[door opens]
We'll be with you in five.
[line dialing]
[somber music playing]
[breathing shakily]
Hello. sweetheart. how's your day?
You lied to me.
What are you talking about?
[sniffles]
You lied about Dad and David.
How could you do that to me?
[Nathalie] Hang on. Uh…
- Where are you? We'll talk. okay?
- [sobs]
No. [exhales]
Tell me where you are.
- [sobs]
- Max.
Max. just tell me so I can get there.
- [sobs]
- Please. Max.
[officer] Gentlemen. you ready?
[sobs]
- [line beeps]
- Damn it.
[Mélanie] Rarely have I seen so many
violations of the GIGN's code of ethics.
not to mention the law.
You pursued the suspect on your own.
and got him killed.
You acted in self-defense.
but the damage is still done.
If it were up to me.
you'd be tried. convicted.
A suspended sentence at the very least.
And probably prison.
if we're being honest.
But I don't think it would be beneficial.
Not for the GIGN. nor the military police.
if the two heroes of the hour.
who put an end
to a bomber's murderous rampage.
were publicly disciplined.
Am I right. General?
Yes.
The fact remains that your actions
have no place in the armed forces.
and even less in the GIGN.
Commander. I expected more from you.
You took a new recruit
on a clandestine operation.
You are hereby suspended
pending early retirement.
We never want to see you again.
And you. Villiers. your inexperience
doesn't justify such a lapse of judgment.
The disciplinary board
will decide your fate in two weeks.
Until then.
you are prohibited from participating
in any operations or training
without the agreement
of your new section leader.
I remind you that we have not yet found
the 500 kilos of explosives.
I don't know what the final decision
will be regarding you. but let me say.
this kind of crap has no place at GIGN.
You're both dismissed.
[music fades]
[door opens]
[poignant music playing]
[David] Max!
What else you wanna tell me?
I gave everything to join the force.
Everything!
All I wanted was to be like you and Dad!
But what does it even matter?
You're not heroes! It's all bullshit!
[poignant music continues]
[engine starts]
[tense music playing]
[sighs]
[man] It's not my fault!
Fuck! What do we do?
Just think. damn it! Think! Shit!
[woman crying]
[suspenseful music playing]
[man] Shh!
I've gone too far now.
I'm not going back. Fuck.
It's not my fault. It's not my fault.
Sweetheart. you know
where Daddy's office is?
Get yourself there.
Find a place to hide. Don't make a sound.
Don't come out unless I'm telling you
it's safe to come out.
Understand?
I'll find you when it's safe. I promise.
And you?
[Amal] Don't worry. you know us.
You know we're strong. you know
we won't stop fighting until we win.
Get ready to move.
On my signal. you're gonna run.
I'll come get you.
- Go on. sweetheart.
- Run.
- It's okay.
- Run. go on!
[tense music playing]
Calm down. Calm down.
Calm down!
[beeps]
[man] You! Get up!
Get the fuck up! Come on!
You too!
On your feet!
- Shit!
- [gunshots]
[both groan]
[screams]
[intense music playing]
Just stay with me. Stay with me.
[beeps]
- [man 1] Police!
- [man 2] Go! Go!
[man 3] He planted explosives.
- My daughter's in the lab!
- Get out.
I'm a father too. okay?
I'm a father too.
I'm going to get your daughter.
[Amal] I'll find you
when it's safe. I promise.
[intense music continues]
- [metal rattling]
- [music fades]
[metal shutter closes]
[ominous music playing]
[music turns suspenseful]
A HUMAN TRAGEDY IN THE FACE
OF NATIONAL SECURITY
LINA MAYARD 9 YEARS OLD
A LIFE CUT SHORT
[music turns dramatic]
[dramatic music continues]
[music fades]
Okay. you can sleep over at Nina's
but only if you promise you'll rehearse.
- [Manon] Okay.
- Don't go anywhere.
Don't worry. we're going to school first
to practice for a bit.
Then we'll go to Nina's.
- Night. Mom. Love you.
- I love you too. sweetie.
- [elevator chimes]
- [doors open]
[poignant music playing]
I've been suspended.
What?
I told Max everything.
I told him he's my son.
And then. that idiot decided
to tell the inspector the truth.
even though he was in the clear.
[sighs]
You were going to end up in prison
so that Max could stay on the force? How…?
- What kind of a plan was that?
- [sighs]
Jess. you know
I made a promise to Laurent.
I swore to him I would take care of Max.
I promised him I'd take care of Max.
I promised him.
COMMIT FOR LIFE
NATIONAL MILITARY POLICE
- [inaudible dialogue]
- [poignant music continues]
[Jess] And you really think
that's why you're doing all this?
That's bullshit.
If you hadn't made that promise.
you'd still be acting this way.
The truth is you feel guilty
about what happened.
You can't get rid of that feeling
no matter how hard you try.
Who's going to give you permission
to start living?
When will you let yourself
be with your family?
You're not guilty of anything.
[David] I am. though.
Because I did. I did betray Laurent.
I shouldn't have said what I said to him
right before the mission…
[sobbing]
And I'm guilty of not looking out for Max.
- [David sobbing]
- [poignant music continues]
I wasn't there for him.
for my son. for fuck's sake.
I wasn't there for my kid.
[David sobs]
And I've never been there for you either.
not really. I haven't.
[sobbing]
I'm there for everyone.
except for my family.
You needed me and I wasn't there.
[poignant music intensifies]
[screams]
[sniffles]
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
[screams]
[music fades]
[playing "Nocturne No. 13"
by Frédéric Chopin]
- [weapons cocking]
- [piano stops]
[menacing music playing]
I'm so sorry.
[music fades]
[dramatic music playing]
[music ends]
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm